

DAPHNE **SMIT**

FRONTEND DEVELOPER

CONTACT

hi@daphnesmit.nl

www.daphnesmit.nl

SOCIALS

in LinkedIn

Github

Instagram

Website

LANGUAGES

DUTCH • • • • • • FRENCH • • • • •



ABOUT ME

I am a passionate Freelance **Frontend Developer** - based in Amsterdam - with **professional working experience since 2010**. I am a Big fan of **open source**. Current stack usually contains: **React, Typescript, NextJS/Remix, Chakra-ui,** my own strict **eslint setup, Storybook, Github Actions.**I have great eye for detail and am always looking for patterns and consistency in my work.



WORKING EXPERIENCE

> BRAVOURE - FREELANCE FE DEVELOPER

MAY 2022 - NOW

New website for creative design agency Natwerk. The end product was a multilingual website full of entry and exit animations using **framer-motion**. Build on **NextJS** with **next-translate** as an **ISR** website using the Craft CMS **GraphQL** API to generate the content and pages.

> SDU - FREELANCE FRONTEND DEVELOPER

JUN 2020 - NOW

SDU provides digital products for Fiscalists and Lawyers in The Netherlands. Worked on the **Titan design system component library**. Helped developing their **SSR** platform in **NextJS** with **Typescript** deployed using **Docker** images on **Kubernetes** using **Helmfiles**. Also made two tools in **NodeJS**: one print API in **GraphQL** using Gotenberg, **Bull queueing** and **Redis** and an application management service to manage user roles per website. For testing we use **Cypress** and **Jest/React testing library**.

> FREELANCE FRONTEND DEVELOPER

APR 2020 - NOW

As a Freelance Frontend Developer I have been working for various clients like Aurum, Honig and Doorb. Usually with **React/Nextjs/Typescript** and **CSS-in-JS** libs like **Emotion**, **Chakra-ui** or **styled-components** or plain **Javascript** with **Sass** or **Tailwind**.

> DEPT AGENCY - FRONTEND DEVELOPER APR 2014 - MAR 2020

Dept is an international digital agency with offices around the world. Worked for client like **Etos**, **Gall**, **Maandag**, **Union**, **Oxxio**, **Brenntag** and **Bugaboo**. From Vanilla JS, React, Salesforce Commerce Cloud, Umbraco CMS to Azure devops. Build for **Etos** their **first Benelux webshop** and even fully **a11y**. From medior frontend developer I grew to a lead/principal position. Coaching junior developers to make them become even better!

> ICEMOBILE - FRONTEND DEVELOPER

NOV 2013 - OCT 2014

IceMobile is a mobile digital agency. I was responsible for creating The Bright Admin Console to manage saving digital stamps for supermarkets. It was made in **EmberJS**. Learned here to work in mature **scrum** teams.

> MATTMO - FRONTEND DEVELOPER

NOV 2010 - OCT 2013

Mattmo is a small design studio in the center of Amsterdam. Learned the basics of **Javascript**, **HTML** & **CSS** here.



EDUCATION

> HOGESCHOOL VAN AMSTERDAM - BSC

2006 - 2010

Communication & Multimedia Design, Interactive Media

> UTRECHT UNIVERSITY

2004 - 2005

Information & Communication sciences